Guide to the Alvin Saunders Johnson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1907-1966; Series III; 2.25 linear feet (5 boxes)
  - Addresses and Essays
    - "New School Twentieth Anniversary Address", 1944 (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - "Race in the World of Tomorrow", 1944 (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - "Washington and de Gaulle", 1945 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "American-Scandinavian Foundation Address", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "The Economic Problem of Germany", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Einstein University Address", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Employment Discrimination and the Law", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "I Am an American Luncheon Address", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "The Influx of Intellectuals", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Liberal Education Fact and Fiction", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "The Library's Post War Obligations", 1945 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Minorities Under American Democracy", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "New School Commencement Address", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "University of Nebraska Convocation Address", 1946 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Address", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - "Denazification", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - "The Development of a Liberal", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - "Discrimination in Education", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "Horace Kallen Address", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "The Jewish Problem in America", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "The Meaning of Student Exchange", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "New School Commencement Address", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - "Palestine: A Possible Solution", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Places for Displaced Persons", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Social Value of the Jewish Farm Movement", 1947 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Cleopatra and the Roman Chamber of Commerce", 1949 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "The Good Citizen", 1949 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Religion and Social Justice", 1949 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Notes on Italy", 1951 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "The School of Political Science", 1951 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "Introduction to The New Vanguard ed. by Don Wolfe", 1952 (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - "The Continuing Revolution", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "Government by Concurrent Minorities", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "In Memory of Wesley Mitchell", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "The New School Associates", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "On Xenophon and Dr. Strauss", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "One World, or Two, or Three", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "Party and Ideology in America", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "The Real Menace to Capitalism", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "Thomas Dewey: A New Deal in the American Spirit", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "The Scientific Future of Israel", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - "Adult Education", 1953 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "Forward to Lucille Milner's Book", 1953 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "Israel Rogosin", 1953 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "This I Believe", 1953 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "On Bryn Hoode", 1954 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "The Rising Flood of Population", 1954 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "The Challenge of Soviet Education", 1956 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "The National Principle", 1956 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "The Russian Bear Walks Again", 1956 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "Introduction to David Abrahamson's Book", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "A Retrospect", 1958 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "The University in Exile", 1958 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "Birthday Address", 1960 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "New School Background", 1961 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "A Tribute to Else Staudinger", 1966 (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - "Adult Education and the New Era", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "Adult Education Comes of Age", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "Adult Education: Historical", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "America, France, and Belgium", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "American Fascism", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "American Policy and European Nationalization", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "The Army Vs. the Educator", undated (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - "Creative Culture and the Economy", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "Discrimination and Law", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "Economics and the Psychology of War" (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "Education's Golden Age", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "Education for the Ex-Soldier", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "Exit Educational Bias", undated (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - "The Future of Adult Education", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "The Great American Virtue", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "In Memory of Selig Hecht", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "Industrial Society and Democracy", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "Introduction to Dr. Abraham's Essay", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "Liberal Education and the Adult Educator", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "Love of Friends", undated (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - "The Magic Word Capitalism", undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - "The Making of a Democratic Law" (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - "The Meaning of Germany's Fall", undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - "Our Case Against Soviet Russia", undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - "Our First Line of Defense", undated (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - "The Rehabilitation of Europe", undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - "Relief from Farm Relief", undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - "Seymour on Discrimination", undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - "To Dr. Hans Simons", undated (Box 12, Folder 213)
  - Books
    - Pioneer's Progress early draft - ms. (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - Pioneer's Progress author's preface (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter I - ms. (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter II - ms. (Box 12, Folder 217)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter III - ms. (Box 12, Folder 218)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter IV - ms. (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter V - ms. (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter VI - ms. (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter VII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter VIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 223)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter IX - ms. (Box 13, Folder 224)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter X - ms. (Box 13, Folder 225)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XI - ms (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XII - ms (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 228)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XIV - ms. (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XV - ms. (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XVI - ms. (Box 13, Folder 231)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XVII - ms (Box 13, Folder 232)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XVIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XIX - ms. (Box 13, Folder 234)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XX - ms. (Box 13, Folder 235)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXI - ms (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 238)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXIV - ms (Box 13, Folder 239)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXV - ms. (Box 13, Folder 240)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXVI - ms. (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXVII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 242)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXVIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXIX - ms. (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXX - ms. (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXI - ms. (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXIII - ms. (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXIV - ms. (Box 13, Folder 249)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXV - ms. (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - Pioneer's Progress chapter XXXVI - ms. (Box 13, Folder 251)
    - Introduction to Economics, 1909 (Box 14)
    - Introduction to Economics, revised, 1922 (Box 14)
    - The Professor and the Petticoat, 1914 (Box 14)
    - Deliver Us From Dogma, 1934 (Box 14)
    - Spring Storm, 1936 (Box 14)
    - The Public Library—A Peoples University, 1938 (Box 14)
    - The Clock of History, 1946 (Box 15)
    - Pioneer's Progress, 1952 (Box 15)
    - Essays in Social Economics, 1954 (Box 15)
    - The Battle of the Wild Turkey and Other Tales, 1961 (Box 15)
    - Ideas Are High Explosives, 1962 (Box 15)
    - A Touch of Color and Other Tales, 1963 (Box 15)
    - New World for Old, 1965 (Box 15)